{
    "questions" : [
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [1~2] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "30_1_img",
            "option_1"      : "① ",
            "option_2"      : "② ",
            "option_3"      : "③ ",
            "option_4"      : "④ ",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : There are a lot of people, shall we just walk?\nMan : I have to go to the 6th floor, isn't it hard?\nWoman : I think it will take a long time to wait. Just go to the stairs.",
            "correctAnswer" : "① ",
            "score"         : "3",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [1~2] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "30_2_img",
            "option_1"      : "① ",
            "option_2"      : "② ",
            "option_3"      : "③ ",
            "option_4"      : "④ ",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Are you copying the meeting materials?\nMan : Yes. You just need to copy a few more copies.\nWoman : Is that so? I'll be in the conference room first, so bring it.",
            "correctAnswer" : "② ",
            "score"         : "3",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [3~6]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 이어 질 수있는 말을 고르십시오",
            "question"      : "3. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  저도 늦게 왔는데요.",
            "option_2"      : "②  빨리 시작하면 더 좋지요.",
            "option_3"      : "③  처음이라 아직 잘 모르겠어요.",
            "option_4"      : "④  일이 어렵지 않아서 좋겠어요.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : I'm sorry for being late. My part-time job ended late.\nWoman : It's okay. How about a new part-time job?\nMan : It's my first time, so I don't know yet.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  처음이라 아직 잘 모르겠어요.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },        
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [3~6]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 이어 질 수있는 말을 고르십시오",
            "question"      : "4. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  연락도 안 했는데 어떻게 왔지?",
            "option_2"      : "②  수업에 빠졌으니까 잘 모를 거야.",
            "option_3"      : "③  바쁜 일이 있어서 결석을 자주 해.",
            "option_4"      : "④  무슨 일이 있는지 한번 전화해 볼까?",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Why did Minsu finish his absence?\nMan : I've never been here without contact.\nWoman : Shall we call you to see what's going on?",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  무슨 일이 있는지 한번 전화해 볼까?",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [3~6]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 이어 질 수있는 말을 고르십시오",
            "question"      : "5. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  내가 기차 시간부터 알아볼게요.",
            "option_2"      : "②  차로 가는 게 더 편하고 좋잖아요.",
            "option_3"      : "③  운전해서 가면 피곤할 것 같아서요.",
            "option_4"      : "④  예매를 안 하면 표가 없을 것 같아요.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Why don't we go by train for this business trip to Busan?\nWoman : The train? You asked me to go by car yesterday.\nMan : I think I'll be tired if I drive.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  운전해서 가면 피곤할 것 같아서요.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [3~6]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 이어 질 수있는 말을 고르십시오",
            "question"      : "6. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  사람이 많아서 기다려야 해요.",
            "option_2"      : "②  아직 식사 시간이 아니라서 그래요.",
            "option_3"      : "③  저도 그 식당에 한번 가 봤으면 좋겠어요.",
            "option_4"      : "④  텔레비전에 나오더니 그새 유명해졌나 봐요.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : It's been a long time since we came to this restaurant together.\nMan : That's right. But why are there so many customers? I didn't do that before.\nWoman: I think she became famous after she appeared on TV.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  텔레비전에 나오더니 그새 유명해졌나 봐요.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [7~10] 다음은 무엇에 대한 내용인지 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "7. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  영화배우의 외모",
            "option_2"      : "②  영화배우의 인기",
            "option_3"      : "③  영화배우의 연기력",
            "option_4"      : "④  영화배우의 출연작",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Oh, this movie is really sad. I don't know how much I cried when the female lead cried at the end.\nMan : I didn't know Han Yumi was so good at acting. I thought it was popular because it was pretty, but I saw it again.\nWoman : Isn't it? All the movies starring the actor are worth watching.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  영화배우의 연기력",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [7~10] 다음은 무엇에 대한 내용인지 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "8. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  습관을 고치는 방법",
            "option_2"      : "②  습관을 없애는 이유",
            "option_3"      : "③  습관과 생각의 관계",
            "option_4"      : "④  습관이 생기는 상황",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : It's not as easy as you think to fix bad habits, is it? Because habits are actions that are repeated without realizing themselves under certain conditions. It's hard not to act when you're in a bad habit. Rather than that, it’s better to change to other actions you can do in that situation.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  습관을 고치는 방법",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [7~10] 다음은 무엇에 대한 내용인지 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "9. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  자동차 보험의 필요성",
            "option_2"      : "②  높은 보험료의 문제점",
            "option_3"      : "③  자동차 사고의 위험성",
            "option_4"      : "④  교통사고 후 처리 순서",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : If you suddenly get into a car accident, you don't know what to do. In this case, it is car insurance that takes care of the things that happened due to the accident and solves the necessary money. Normally, you may think that insurance premiums are a waste, but car insurance is the minimum preparation for accidents that can happen like this.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  자동차 보험의 필요성",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [7~10] 다음은 무엇에 대한 내용인지 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "10. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  사고 방지 대책",
            "option_2"      : "②  사고 피해 정도",
            "option_3"      : "③  사고 발생 원인",
            "option_4"      : "④  사고 처리 결과",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : This is the news of an accident that happened overnight. There was an accident where the sign of the building fell in Sangam-dong at 4 a.m. today. The street tree was broken due to this accident, so we have been experiencing inconvenience in traffic until now. The accident occurred early in the morning, so there was no one passing by nearby, so fortunately, there was no casualties.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  사고 피해 정도",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [11~13] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 4점)",
            "question"      : "11. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  남자는 한 달 전에 이사를 했다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  여자는 이사 시간이 길어 힘들었다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  여자는 해야 할 일들이 많아 정신이 없다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  남자는 이사 후에 정리할 일이 많지 않았다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : You finished moving well, didn't you?\nWoman : Yes. I didn't have much luggage, so I finished quickly. But there are a lot of things to pay attention to even after moving. I've organized my things to do, but I'm out of my mind.\nMan : I also need to connect the phone to the Internet. I think it took me a month to finish organizing it.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  여자는 해야 할 일들이 많아 정신이 없다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [11~13] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 4점)",
            "question"      : "12. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  인주시는 다양한 문화 시설을 가지고 있다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  인주시는 교통이 편리해 쉽게 방문할 수 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  인주시는 외국인이 가장 많이 방문한 도시이다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  인주시는 여러 가지 체험 프로그램을 만들었다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Inju City has been selected as 'the city of Korea that foreigners want to visit the most'. Until a few years ago, transportation was inconvenient and there were few cultural facilities in Inju, so there were not many tourists. For the past 3 years, Inju has been actively informing about the beautiful natural environment. In addition, by developing various experience programs for foreigners, the number of foreign tourists has increased.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  인주시는 여러 가지 체험 프로그램을 만들었다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [11~13] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 4점)",
            "question"      : "13. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  오늘 강연은 질문과 대답으로 이루어진다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  질문에 대한 강사의 대답을 미리 받아 두었다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  이소영 씨는 해외에서 강연을 활발히 하고 있다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  영상물을 통해 이소영 씨의 강연을 들을 수 있다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : How are you, teenagers? Today's instructor is Lee So-young, who is actively volunteering abroad. Today's lecture will be held in the form of questions and answers specifically. I have a question from you in advance. Mr. Lee So-young will answer about this. And I'll give you a chance to ask your questions directly. First of all, let's watch Lee So-young's volunteer site as a video.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  오늘 강연은 질문과 대답으로 이루어진다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [14~17]다음 대화를 듣고 남자가 어떤 생각을 하고 있는지 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "14. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  감기는 시간이 지나야 낫는다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  목이 따뜻해야 감기에 안 걸린다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  약을 안 먹으면 감기가 더 심해진다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  물을 마셔도 기침을 하면 쉬어야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Even though I took cold medicine, I still have a sore throat and cough.\nMan : Whether you take medicine or not, you have to get better after a cold. I think it's better to just take a good rest and warm your neck and drink a lot of lukewarm water than to take medicine.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  감기는 시간이 지나야 낫는다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [14~17]다음 대화를 듣고 남자가 어떤 생각을 하고 있는지 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "15. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  음악이 없으면 딴 생각을 하게 된다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  음악을 듣는 것은 집중에 도움이 된다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  공부하면서 음악을 듣는 것은 좋지 않다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  외국 노래를 듣는 것은 공부에 방해가 된다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Can you study while listening to music? Listening to music gets in the way of studying......\nMan : I listen to music when I can't concentrate while studying. Then you can't hear the sounds around you and don't think about anything else. Especially if you listen to foreign songs or classical music, you can study well.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  음악을 듣는 것은 집중에 도움이 된다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [14~17]다음 대화를 듣고 남자가 어떤 생각을 하고 있는지 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "16. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  운동을 잘하려면 목표를 갖는 것이 중요하다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  상대방을 의식하며 운동하면 오래 하기 어렵다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  운동을 할 때는 다른 사람과 같이 하는 것이 좋다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  효과적으로 운동을 하려면 계획한 시간을 지켜야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman: It's not easy to exercise as much as an hour of goal. Sir, is there any good way to exercise as much as the time you planned? Man : Yes, it's better to do exercise with someone else than alone. If there is someone who works out with you, you will be conscious of that person, so the exercise time will be longer. In particular, if the other person exercises better than you, you will work harder because you want to do well.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  운동을 할 때는 다른 사람과 같이 하는 것이 좋다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [14~17]다음 대화를 듣고 남자가 어떤 생각을 하고 있는지 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "17. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  상황에 맞게 아이를 대해야 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  항상 같은 태도로 아이를 대해야 한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  아이가 원하는 것을 들어주어야 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  아이가 떼를 쓸 때는 가만히 두어야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : At home, the child doesn't listen to me even if I use a flock, but outside, I just listen to it because of people's eyes. What should I do?\nMan : When a child swarms in a crowded place, parents are embarrassed and it's easy to listen to the child. But if the standards are different when you're at home and when you're outside, your child will feel confused and spend more. It will be difficult at first, but the attitude of parents should always be the same, both at home and outside.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  항상 같은 태도로 아이를 대해야 한다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [18~20] 다음 대화를 듣고 여자가 할 행동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "18. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  양파를 썬다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  당면을 삶는다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  채소를 볶는다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  요리책을 살펴본다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Well, I washed all the onions and carrots....... The ingredients are all ready.\nMan : Yes. I think I'm almost done preparing the ingredients. What should we do now? Well, I need to slice the onions. In the meantime, are you going to live the noodles?\nWoman : The noodles? Don't you have to stir-fry vegetables first?\nMan : no It's right to boil it first. I saw it in the cookbook.\nWoman : Is that so? I got it.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  당면을 삶는다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [18~20] 다음 대화를 듣고 여자가 할 행동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "19. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  시험장으로 들어간다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  시험 신청서를 작성한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  검사 결과를 기다린다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  지하에 있는 검사실로 간다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : I've finished writing the application form here. What should I do now?\nMan : You can do an eye exam first and then take the license test.\nWoman : Is that so? Where do you do the test.\nMan : Take your receipt here and go to the examination room in the basement. I'll let you know the results when the eye exam is over.\nWoman : Can I take the license test right after the test?\nMan : Yes. If there is no problem with the result, you can see it.\nWoman : Yes, I got it.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  지하에 있는 검사실로 간다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [18~20] 다음 대화를 듣고 여자가 할 행동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "20. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  전시장에 책자를 놓아둔다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  책자를 남자에게 보여 준다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  책자의 사진 위치를 바꾼다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  전시회 준비 사항을 확인한다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : How are you getting ready for the exhibition?\nWoman : Yes, I'm making a booklet for the exhibition hall now. Can you take a look.\nMan : Well, that's good. Oh, but I think the pictures of the works here are too small. Why don't you change the size or location of the photo?\nWoman : Anyway, I was going to change the positions now.\nMan : Is that so? Then please show me after making it again.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  책자의 사진 위치를 바꾼다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [21~22] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "21. 들은 내용으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오. ",
            "option_1"      : "①  여자는 일을 많이 해서 힘들어한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  여자는 오랜 기간 공연을 하지 않았다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  여자는 체력 관리에 신경을 못 쓰고 있다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  여자는 일 년에 여러 작품을 하지 않는다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : I enjoyed the performance today. It was a very powerful stage. Physical strength is also important if you want to perform a musical for such a long time.\nWoman : Yes. If you're a good actor, you should be good at singing, dancing, and acting, but stamina is also important. So I'm paying more attention to my physical fitness management as I get older.\nMan : Oh, I see. Then is that why you don't do a lot of works?\nWoman : Of course there is a reason for that. But it takes me a while to understand the role properly, so I try not to do more than one or two works a year.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  여자는 일 년에 여러 작품을 하지 않는다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [21~22] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "22.  여자는 누구인지 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  공연 관람객",
            "option_2"      : "②  뮤지컬 배우",
            "option_3"      : "③  공연 관계자",
            "option_4"      : "④  뮤지컬 연출가",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : I enjoyed the performance today. It was a very powerful stage. Physical strength is also important if you want to perform a musical for such a long time.\nWoman : Yes. If you're a good actor, you should be good at singing, dancing, and acting, but stamina is also important. So I'm paying more attention to my physical fitness management as I get older.\nMan : Oh, I see. Then is that why you don't do a lot of works?\nWoman : Of course there is a reason for that. But it takes me a while to understand the role properly, so I try not to do more than one or two works a year.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  뮤지컬 배우",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [23~24] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "23. 남자는 무엇을 하고 있는지 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  서비스의 성과를 알려 주고 있다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  서비스의 종류에 대해 설명하고 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  서비스의 활용 방안을 소개하고 있다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  서비스의 내용에 대해 홍보하고 있다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : It is said that the post office in Seoul recently started a special postal service. I'll talk with postmaster Kim Won-il. Hello ?\nMan : Yes. I've been using e-mails and text messages a lot these days, so I don't send letters more and more. Actually, even if you try to send a letter, there aren't many mailboxes, so there will be a lot of inconveniences. So, our post office started accepting mail visits a while ago. If you apply by phone or online, our staff will visit you in person and receive a letter. You can easily send a letter from home, so please use it a lot in the future.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  서비스의 내용에 대해 홍보하고 있다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [23~24] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "24. 이 서비스를 시작한 이유를 고르십시오. ",
            "option_1"      : "①  우편물을 안전하게 배송하기 위해",
            "option_2"      : "②  우체국 직원의 업무를 줄이기 위해",
            "option_3"      : "③  우편 업무를 효율적으로 처리하기 위해",
            "option_4"      : "④  더 편리한 우편 서비스를 제공하기 위해",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : It is said that the post office in Seoul recently started a special postal service. I'll talk with postmaster Kim Won-il. Hello ?\nMan : Yes. I've been using e-mails and text messages a lot these days, so I don't send letters more and more. Actually, even if you try to send a letter, there aren't many mailboxes, so there will be a lot of inconveniences. So, our post office started accepting mail visits a while ago. If you apply by phone or online, our staff will visit you in person and receive a letter. You can easily send a letter from home, so please use it a lot in the future.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  더 편리한 우편 서비스를 제공하기 위해",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [25~26] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오.",
            "question"      : "25. 여자의 생각으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (4점)",
            "option_1"      : "①  봉사 활동은 대학 생활을 의미 있게 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  지킬 수 없는 약속은 하지 않는 것이 좋다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  글로 남기는 것은 더 큰 책임감을 갖게 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  책임감 있게 행동하는 것은 쉬운 일이 아니다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Today, I'd like to talk about the power of writing. I've done an experiment like this before. After asking the students if they were thinking of volunteering, I had one team fill out an application and the other team make a promise only with words. However, 57% of the students who wrote the application were in the volunteer work, while only 17% of the students who made a verbal promise participated. Why did this difference appear? That’s because writing makes you act more responsibly.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  글로 남기는 것은 더 큰 책임감을 갖게 한다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [25~26] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오.",
            "question"      : "26. 여자가 제시한 주장의 근거로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (3점)",
            "option_1"      : "①  실험 결과",
            "option_2"      : "②  조사 자료",
            "option_3"      : "③  전문가의 의견",
            "option_4"      : "④  신문 기사 내용",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Today, I'd like to talk about the power of writing. I've done an experiment like this before. After asking the students if they were thinking of volunteering, I had one team fill out an application and the other team make a promise only with words. However, 57% of the students who wrote the application were in the volunteer work, while only 17% of the students who made a verbal promise participated. Why did this difference appear? That’s because writing makes you act more responsibly.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  실험 결과",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [27~28] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "27. 여자의 생각으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  나무 계단은 등산객의 안전에 도움이 된다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  등산할 때는 계단보다는 흙길로 가는 것이 좋다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  시민들의 반응을 보고 계단을 설치하도록 해야 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  산에서 길을 잃어버리지 않도록 등산로를 늘려야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : There are many places with wooden stairs on hiking trails these days. The citizens' response to this is very good. The place that used to be a dirt road has been neatly organized, making it easier to climb the mountain. Also, they clearly distinguish the hiking trails, so you don't have to worry about getting lost in the mountains.\nMan : Just because the wooden stairs are made of wood doesn't mean it's not bad for the environment. In the process of installing the stairs, it can harm the mountain, and the land is contaminated because of the oil applied to the stairs. Don't just think too much about people's convenience, you should also protect nature.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  나무 계단은 등산객의 안전에 도움이 된다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [27~28] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "28. 남자의 생각이나 태도로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  여자의 말에 강한 불만을 드러내고 있다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  여자의 주장을 적극적으로 받아들이고 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  여자의 의견에 분명한 반대 입장을 보이고 있다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  여자의 생각에 동의하며 자신의 의견을 밝히고 있다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : There are many places with wooden stairs on hiking trails these days. The citizens' response to this is very good. The place that used to be a dirt road has been neatly organized, making it easier to climb the mountain. Also, they clearly distinguish the hiking trails, so you don't have to worry about getting lost in the mountains.\nMan : Just because the wooden stairs are made of wood doesn't mean it's not bad for the environment. In the process of installing the stairs, it can harm the mountain, and the land is contaminated because of the oil applied to the stairs. Don't just think too much about people's convenience, you should also protect nature.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  여자의 생각에 동의하며 자신의 의견을 밝히고 있다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [29~30] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오.",
            "question"      : "29. 이 뉴스의 제목으로 가장 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (4점)",
            "option_1"      : "①  주차장, 차 세울 곳 없어",
            "option_2"      : "②  중개업 믿었다가 큰코다쳐",
            "option_3"      : "③  렌터카 가격 지역마다 달라",
            "option_4"      : "④  잠자던 자가용으로 수익 올려",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : I heard that there are people who use their own car to make a profit, which was only parked in the parking lot. Reporter Park Sang-hyun covered it.\nMan : Recently, Kim Min-soo is making some income by renting his own car. It's not a lot of money, but they say it's a car maintenance fee. Of course, I was nervous about lending a car at first. However, the brokerage will solve troublesome problems such as rental fees and insurance on your behalf, so now you can trust them and lend them to you. The person who rents it is also cheaper than a rental car, and it is convenient because you can rent a car nearby.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  잠자던 자가용으로 수익 올려",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [29~30] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오.",
            "question"      : "30. 들은 내용으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (3점)",
            "option_1"      : "①  차를 대여할 때 보험 문제는 개인적으로 해결해야 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  가까이 있는 차를 저렴한 가격에 빌릴 수 있어 편리하다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  렌터카 회사를 통해서 자가용을 빌리면 대여료가 더 싸다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  개인의 차를 대여해 주다 보면 귀찮은 문제가 많이 생긴다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : I heard that there are people who use their own car to make a profit, which was only parked in the parking lot. Reporter Park Sang-hyun covered it.\nMan : Recently, Kim Min-soo is making some income by renting his own car. It's not a lot of money, but they say it's a car maintenance fee. Of course, I was nervous about lending a car at first. However, the brokerage will solve troublesome problems such as rental fees and insurance on your behalf, so now you can trust them and lend them to you. The person who rents it is also cheaper than a rental car, and it is convenient because you can rent a car nearby.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  가까이 있는 차를 저렴한 가격에 빌릴 수 있어 편리하다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        }
    ]
}
